using a smart contract you can store
使用智能合约，您可以将数据永久存储在以太坊中
data permanently on the ethereum
blockchain but it is very expensive to
区块链，但是使用区块链作为数据非常昂贵
use the ethereum blockchain as a data
区块链，但是使用以太坊区块链作为数据非常昂贵
storage today the price of ethereum is
今天存储以太坊的价格为171美元，存储1兆字节的数据
$171 and storing one megabyte of data
will roughly cost you $1,100 in this
在这部影片中大约要花费您1100美元，我将向您展示如何编写
video I'll show you how to write a
simple contract to store arbitrary data
简单的合同，可在区块链上存储任意数据，并简要浏览
on the blockchain and briefly go over an
alternative way to store large data
可靠地存储大型数据变量的另一种方法是存储在一个
variables in solidity are stored in one
of the daily locations storage this is
日常位置存储中可以永久存储数据的位置，
where data can be permanently stored and
these variables are called state
这些变量称为状态变量，就像您的硬盘一样
variables this is like your hard drive
memory variables are only available
内存变量仅在函数执行时可用，这就像
while function is executing this is like
your computer memory call data this is
您的计算机内存调用数据，这是一些函数参数的存储位置
where some function arguments are stored
but we will ignore this one since we
但由于我们不需要了解这一点，因此我们将忽略这一点
don't need to understand this one for
our contract for example variables
我们的合同，例如在合同内在此处声明的变量，但
declared here inside the contract but
outside the functions are state
函数之外是状态变量，它们将存储在
variables and they'll be stored on to
the blockchain variables declared here
函数内部在此处声明的区块链变量仅可用
inside the function are only available
during function call and they won't be
在函数调用期间，它们不会存储在区块链上
stored on to the blockchain
functions and solidity can be
功能和坚固性可分为两种类型的功能
categorized into two types functions
that create transactions on the
在区块链上创建交易的功能
blockchain and functions that don't
functions that create transactions write
创建交易的功能将数据写入区块链，例如更改
data on the blockchain like changing the
valuable state variable which changes
有价值的状态变量，可更改智能合约的状态或
the state of the smart contract or
sending later to another account which
稍后发送到另一个帐户，该帐户会更改已记录帐户的余额
changes the balance of accounts recorded
on the blockchain functions that don't
不会在区块链上不创建任何交易的区块链功能上
create any transaction on the blockchain
are free to call and they do not change
可以免费拨打电话，并且它们不会更改区块链的状态
the state of the blockchain an example
will be a function that reads and
将是一个读取并返回状态变量值的函数
returns the value of the state variable
inside a smart contract now let's put
现在，在智能合约中，我们将上面提到的所有概念放入
all the concepts mentioned above into
code we will create a simple smart
代码，我们将创建一个简单的智能合约来存储文本，让我们为其命名
contract to store text let's name it
simple storage
合同内的简单存储，我们需要声明一个
inside the contract we need to declare a
state variable of type string to store
字符串类型的状态变量来存储文本，我们还需要两个函数
the text we also need two functions a
public function to update the tax
公用函数来更新您设置的税收变量和另一个变量
variable your name is set and another
public function to get the text variable
获取文本变量的公共函数，我们将其命名为更新
we'll name this one get to update the
text variable in our contract we need a
我们合同中的text变量，我们需要一个set函数来获取新字符串
set function to take the new string
value as input in solidity you need to
值作为可靠的输入，您需要在其中声明函数输入的类型
declare the type of function inputs in
our case we have a single input of type
在我们的案例中，对于某些数据类型，我们只有一个字符串类型的输入，包括
string for certain data types including
string you have to explicitly declare
字符串，您必须显式声明数据位置，所以让我们考虑一下
the data location so let's think about
which keyword we need to use either
如果我们使用哪个关键字，那么我们需要使用存储或内存
storage or memory if we use the keyword
storage then we are telling solidity
存储，那么我们要告诉固体，我们的输入是存储的值
that our input is a value stored
somewhere in our contract but that
我们合同中的某处，但事实并非如此，因为您会
cannot be the case since you'll be
providing a value for the input from
为合同外部的输入提供价值，因此我们将声明为
outside the contract so we'll declare as
memory if you accidentally declare as
内存，如果您不小心声明为存储并尝试对其进行编译，则会得到
storage and try to compile it you'll get
a error like this for public functions
对于公共功能输入的此类错误必须声明为内存
inputs must be declared as memory
anyways let's name this input as text
无论如何，让我们将此输入命名为以下划线为前缀的文本
prefixed with an underscore in solidity
it is common practice to prefix function
通常的做法是在函数输入前添加下划线
input with an underscore this is done to
avoid using the same name as state
避免在这种情况下使用与状态变量相同的名称
variables in this case we differentiate
the text variable with our new text
使用下划线作为前缀的新文本输入的文本变量
input by prefixing with an underscore
inside the function we update the text
在函数内部，我们只需将文本变量更新为新值即可
variable to the new value simply by
reassigning it with our input
用我们的输入重新分配它，有两种方法可以从中获取变量
there are two ways to get variables from
a smart contract one way is to write a
智能合约的一种方法是编写一个函数以返回值，并且
function to return the value and the
other way is to let solidity compiler
另一种方法是让Solidity编译器为您编写一个，为什么不使用
write one for you so why not vessel the
DD right one for you all the time well
始终为您正确地选择DD，在某些情况下，
there are cases when it's better to
write your own for example you might
编写自己的示例，例如，您可能想从
want to return multiple values from a
single function call instead of calling
单个函数调用而不是调用两个单独的函数，我将解释
two separate functions I will explain
this in a future video okay so let's go
在以后的视频中，这很好，让我们来看一下获取变量的第一种方法
over the first way of getting variables
writing our own function we need our def
编写我们自己的函数，我们需要我们的def函数返回字符串值
function to return the string value
stored in the text variable so we
存储在文本变量中，因此我们在函数定义中声明了这一点
declared that in our function definition
here with the keyword return followed by
这里是关键字return，后面是我们要返回的值的类型
the type of values we are returning in
our case chain again we need to declare
我们的案例链再次，我们需要声明我们的字符串类型的数据位置
the data location of our string type our
text variable is stored in a contract
文本变量存储在存储的合同中，因此您可能会认为我们需要
stored so you might think that we need
to declare storage here but we need the
在这里声明存储，但我们需要将实际值存储在文本变量中
actual value stored in the text variable
not the reference to the variable so we
不是对变量的引用，因此我们将其声明为内存，我们还需要
will declare it as memory we also need
to tell solidity that this function does
告诉我们，此功能不会修改任何状态变量
not modify any state variables we do
this by using either the keyword view or
通过使用关键字view或简而言之，peer可以使您关心
peer in short beauty cares that your
code does not change the state of the
代码不会更改区块链的状态，对等方声明您的
blockchain and peer declares that your
function does not change the state of
函数不会更改区块链的状态，也不会读取
the blockchain and it also does not read
any state variables for our case we want
对于我们的情况，任何状态变量我们都想读取状态变量，所以我们把
to read the state variable so let's put
the BU keyword in a future video I'll go
未来视频中的BU关键字，我将详细介绍它们，敬请关注
over them in detail so stay tuned inside
the function we just return the text
我们只返回文本变量的函数，我将得到一个函数
variable and I'll get a function is
completed the second way of accessing
完成访问变量的第二种方法是让solidity编译器
variable is to let solidity compiler
automatically create getter functions
自动创建getter函数，我们所要做的就是为我们的状态添加前缀
all we have to do is to prefix our state
variables with a public key word I have
具有公共关键字的变量我必须重新编译并部署我们的合同
to recompile and deploy our contract
you'll see that we have access to public
您会看到我们可以通过执行
state variables by executing the
function with the same name as our
与我们的变量同名的函数，现在让我们编译和测试
variable now let's compile and test the
contract make sure that the compiler is
合同应确保编译器与以下版本中定义的版本兼容
compatible with the version defined in
our smart contract compile and then
我们的智能合约先编译然后部署
deploy
you can see here that we have three
您可以在此处看到我们设置了三个函数来更新税款变量
functions set to update the tax variable
get to get the value stored inside the
获取存储在文本变量中的值，我们还有一个函数
text variable we also have a function
with the same name as a text variable
与文本变量同名，这就是
this is the function that was
automatically created by the compiler we
由编译器自动创建，我们可以更新存储在智能文本中的文本
can update our text stored in a smart
contract by calling set
通过在此处调用集合通知来签订合同
notice here that a transaction was
created also notice here that our cam
在这里还创建了一个通知，如果他持有任何真实的
has spent some ether if he hold any real
ethereum don't worry it didn't spend any
以太坊人不用担心它没有从钱包里花掉任何钱，这只是一个
of it from your wallet this is just a
simulation we can verify that our text
模拟中，我们可以通过调用get来验证文本值是否已更新
value was updated by either calling get
or text
或之前提到的文字，我提到将其存储在
earlier I mentioned that storing that on
the blockchain is very expensive one way
区块链非常昂贵，解决此问题的一种方法是使用IP
to go around this problem is by using IP
FS in short ipfs is a peer-to-peer file
简称ipfs的FS是点对点文件存储，任何人都可以通过以下方式访问该文件存储
storage and anyone can access that up by
knowing the hash of the data so when you
知道数据的哈希值，因此当您将数据上传到ipfs时会得到一个哈希值
upload your data to ipfs you get a hash
bag which is the location of your data
袋，这是您的数据所在的位置，并在我们的智能合约East或IP中
and in our smart contract East or the IP
FS hash in this way you accomplish two
通过这种方式，FS哈希可以完成两件事，为
things store a large amount of data for
cheap and use the smart contract to that
便宜，并使用智能合约使每个人都知道您的数据存储在哪里
everyone know where your data is stored
let me show you a quick example here we
让我给你看一个简单的例子这里有一张猫的照片
have an image of a cat that's been
already uploaded to ipfs we copy the
已经上传到ipfs，我们在合同中复制该图像的哈希值
hash of this image next in our contract
we store the hash now anyone can
我们存储了哈希，现在任何人都可以下载并首先看到猫的图像
download and see the cat image by first
reading the ipfs hash from our contract
从合同中读取ipfs哈希，然后在哈希处访问ipfs
and then accessing ipfs at the hash
in this video we talked about smart
在本视频中，我们讨论了智能合约存储变量存储在
contract storage variables are stored in
three locations storage memory and call
三个位置存储内存和呼叫数据，但在大多数情况下，您只需要
data but in most cases you only need to
consider storage and memory variable
考虑将存储在智能合约中的存储和内存变量称为
stored in smart contracts are called
state variables functions can be
状态变量函数可以分为两类：
categorized into two groups ones that
create transactions on the blockchain
在区块链上创建交易，以及不起作用的交易
and ones that don't functions that don't
create any transactions are declared
创建任何使用关键字视图或对等函数声明的事务
with the keyword view or peer functions
that do create a transaction write data
确实会创建交易的交易会在区块链上写入数据，例如更新
on the blockchain like updating the
value of a state variable stored in your
合约实体中存储的状态变量的值会自动创建
contract solidity automatically creates
functions to return the value of public
函数，用于返回将状态数据存储在智能设备上的公共状态变量的值
state variables storing data on a smart
contract is expensive and by using IP FS
合同很昂贵，通过使用IP FS，您可以有效节省大量
you can effectively save large amount on
data on a smart contract I'm gonna wrap
智能合约的数据，我将在这里总结一下，感谢您的观看和
up around here thanks for watching and
I'll talk to you later
我待会再跟你谈